Francis Gurr

- Sheffield, UK
- francisgurr.com
- in francis-gurr
- Francis-Gurr

Summary

I am a recent Electronic Engineering (MEng) graduate from Durham University. My main interests lie in software development and machine learning.

I enjoy solving complex problems both independently and as part of a team. I am a fast learner and enjoy widening my skill set by challenging myself with personal projects. I have experience working on large long term projects and can work well in a range of team dynamics. Whilst completing projects I am highly motivated, organised and strive to ensure all my work is of a high standard. These attributes have led me to receive a first in every programming assignment throughout my degree.

In my spare time I am a keen rock climber, mountain unicyclist and occasional juggler.

Skills

Most experience with:

Java		Python		С	Ja	IV	ascript		MatLab
Linux		CNNs		LaTeX			German		

Experience with:

C++	React		Express.js		Node.js	
SQL	PHP	E	lectronics	Ī	Graphic De	esign

References

Dr Stefano Giani

- Assistant Professor

 Durham University
- stefano.giani@durham.ac.uk

Colin Reekie

- Head of Development *Q-Free ASA*
- colin.reekie@q-free.com

Experience

Masters Project - 1st Class (80%) Durham University 2019 - 2020

- Supported by Q-Free ASA, a global leader in intelligent transportation systems (ITS).
- The project proposed using road-side video cameras as a non-intrusive alternative to current ITS and infomobility systems.
- Video images were used to determine the speed of vehicles.
- A neural network (YOLOv3) was used for object detection with an accuracy of 98% mAP.
- A Kalman filter was used to track the vehicles.
- I developed Python software to calibrate the camera using road markings, and used C++ to calculate the vehicle speeds.
- The project proved successful and was able to provide vehicle speeds in real-time from road-side camera footage.

R&D Intern *Q-Free ASA, Bristol*

Jul 2019 - Sep 2019

- The continuation of a successful third year design project for which I was project manager.
- Designed and developed an innovative prototype for a non-intrusive roadside detection system for counting and classifing vehicles.
- I developed software in C to generate 2D side profiles of vehicles using data from LiDAR and radar sensors.

Summer Project Durham University, Maths Dept. **Jun 2018 - Feb 2019**

- Co-author of ancillary Python software for an academic paper entitled Quartic Graphs that are Bakry-Émery Curvature Sharp.
- I developed a computer classification algorithm to recursively generate all radius two local configurations of quartic graphs.
- Published in Discrete Mathematics 343(3), DOI: 10.1016/j.disc.2019.111767.

Education

MEng Electronic Engineering - 2:1 Durham University 2015 - 2020

• Took a year out following bereavement as an exam only student.

MChem Chemistry Durham University

2014 - 2015

[]

• Switched course after year one.

A Levels Bournemouth Grammar School

2013 - 2014

• A* Chemistry, A Maths, A Physics, A German.

Personal Projects

Pathfinding Visualiser

2021 - Ongoing

- Currently working on a full stack web application to visually depict pathfinding algorithms in action with real world map data.
- Skills used: Javascript, React, Express.js, Node.js, MySQL.

Sudoku Solver

Summer 2017

- Created a JavaFX app to solve Sudoku problems using a recursive backtracking algorithm.
- Skills used: Java, XML.